The old west meets the far east.
Shanghai Noon is a adventure, action, comedy film directed by Tom Dey.
Chon Wang, a clumsy imperial guard, trails Princess Pei Pei when she's
kidnapped from the Forbidden City and transported to America.
Wang follows her captors to Nevada, where he teams up with an unlikely partner, outcast
outlaw Roy O'Bannon, and tries to spring the princess from her imprisonment.
Chon Wang, played by Jackie Chan.
Roy O'Bannon, played by Owen Wilson.
Princess Pei Pei, played by Lucy Liu.
Nathan Van Cleef, played by Xander Berkeley.
Lo Fong, played by Roger Yuan.
Imperial Guard, played by Yu Rongguang.
Shanghai Noon is a 2000 martial arts western action comedy film directed by Tom Dey in his feature film debut,
written by Alfred Gough and Miles Millar, and starring Jackie Chan, Owen Wilson and Lucy Liu.
It is the first entry in the Shanghai film series.
The film, set in Nevada and other parts of the American West in the 19th century, is a juxtaposition of a Western with a kung fu action
film with extended martial arts sequences, as reflected by its title, which is a wordplay on the notable western High Noon.
It also has elements of slapstick comedy and the "buddy film" genre, featuring two vastly different
heroes (a Chinese Imperial Guard and an American Western outlaw) who team up to stop a crime.
The film premiered in Malaysia in May 19, 2000 and was
released in the United States on May 26, 2000.
It received generally positive reviews from critics.
A sequel, Shanghai Knights, was released in 2003, with
Chan and Wilson reprising their roles.
The film explores themes of princess, rescue,
martial arts, native american, sioux.
The tone is lighthearted.